hay.dk 2019-07-09

# Privacy Policy & Cookies

**PRIVACY POLICY  
**

HAY A/S (Data Controller) markets and sells products under the trademark HAY. In the following HAY A/S is referred to as “HAY”.

HAY takes privacy and security concerns seriously and it is important to us to ensure your personal data is protected when using our services.

Our privacy policy sets out how and why we collect, store, process and share your personal data.

Our privacy policy informs you about your rights in relation to the personal data you share with us.

HAY collects, stores, processes and shares your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection law.

**HAY’s collection of personal data**

_Fulfilment of your order_  
When you place an order in a HAY store, we process information about your name, address, e-mail address, phone number and payment details. The purpose of our processing is to fulfill your order.

The legal basis for the processing is the contractual necessity, cf. GDPR, art. 6 (1)(b).

_Customer service_  
If you contact our customer service team, we will process the personal data you provide us with. Furthermore, we process all your order information, so we can help you in the best possible way, whether you have questions about the status of your order, or if you need to return an item. Our customer service team also has access to all previous correspondence in order to provide you with an optimal service.

The legal basis for the processing is partly the contractual necessity, cf. GDPR, art. 6 (1)(b), partly our legitimate interest in providing you with an optimal service, cf. GDPR, art. 6 (1)(f).

_Design proposals_  
When you submit design proposals, we process information about your name, e-mail address, phone number and other personal data you provide us with.

The legal basis for the processing is partly the contractual necessity for accepted design proposals, cf. GDPR, art. 6 (1)(b), partly our legitimate interest in assessing incoming design proposals, cf. GDPR, art. 6 (1)(f).

_Newsletter_  
When you sign up to our newsletter, we process information about your name and e-mail address. The purpose of our processing is to provide you with our newsletter.

The legal basis for the processing is your consent, cf. GDPR, art. 6 (1)(a).

_Our website_   
HAY constantly strives to give you the very best user and shopping experience on our website. We do that in different ways, but an important part of it is being able to track your browsing on our site. We do that by using cookies. You can read more about cookies below. We also use your browsing data to recommend products that we think may be of interest to you.

 _Custom Cash  
_ When you use Custom Cash in a HAY store, we process information about your Customer App ID, name, address, city, country, email address, mobile phone number, passport number, credit card information, bank account information, date of your purchase, information on the relevant goods, total amount of purchase, including VAT, VAT refund amount, invoice/receipt number. The Purpose of the processing is to create and issue the Tax Free Form. The legal basis for the processing is the contractual necessity, cf. GDPR art. 6 (1)(b)

 _Other contact  
_ When you contact us, we process the personal data you provide us with. Furthermore, we process information about your name and other personal data you provide us with when engaging with our social media platforms. The purpose of the processing is to fulfill your request and provide you with an optimal service. The legal basis for the processing is our legitimate interest in fulfilling your request, cf. GDPR, art. 6 (1)(f).

**Security  
** HAY has implemented several security measures to protect your personal information from being destroyed, lost/modified, unauthorized disclosure and accidental access. We always strive to protect your personal data in the best possible way.

**Disclosure to third parties  
** We share your personal data with third parties who work with us to provide products and services. We share your personal data with the following categories:

\- Suppliers (e.g. warehouse partners, payment solution suppliers, carrier partners, customer service suppliers)

\- Affiliates (for internal business purposes, including e.g. technical operations)

\- Public and governmental authorities, if required by law

Third parties are prohibited from using or disclosing your personal data for any purpose other than to provide this assistance, except to the extent required by law.

Your personal data may be processed outside the EEA by third parties, e.g. in countries ensuring an adequate level of protection or in accordance with the Privacy Shield Framework.

 **Storage Period  
** We store and process the personal data as long as it is necessary to meet the above-mentioned purposes or as long as required by law. The storage period depends on the nature of the data and the purpose for storing the data.

**Your Rights  
** You have a number of rights in connection with our processing of your personal data.

\- You are entitled to access to and copy of your personal data that has been processed by us

\- You are under certain conditions entitled to be forgotten, meaning you can file a request asking that we delete all personal data we have registered about you

\- You are under certain conditions entitled to demand that we limit our processing of your personal data

\- You are under certain conditions entitled to object to our processing of your personal data

\- You are entitled to have incorrect personal data corrected

\- You are under certain conditions entitled to demand that we transmit your personal data to you or another data controller in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format (“data portability”)

\- You are entitled to complain about how we process your personal data

\- You may at any given time withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal data when our processing is based on your consent

If you wish to lodge a complaint to the Danish Data Protection Authority, please contact:

The Danish Data Protection Agency (Datatilsynet)

Borgergade 28, 5  
1300 København K, Denmark  
Phone: +45 3319 3200  
Email: [dt@datatilsynet.dk](http://dt@datatilsynet.dk/ "mail to: dt@datatilsynet.dk")

**  
Policy changes  
** HAY’s privacy policy will be updated continuously, so please keep updated with the latest version of our privacy policy when using our services.

 **Contact  
** Feel free to contact us if you have any questions regarding the protection of your personal data or wish to use your rights under it. You can contact us at [hay@hay.dk](mailto:hay@hay.dk "mail to: hay@hay.dk")Company address  
HAY A/S  
Havnen 1  
8700 Horsens, Denmark  
Phone: +45 4282 0373  
Email: [hay@hay.dk](mailto:hay@hay.dk "mail to: hay@hay.dk")

**COOKIES**  
HAY uses cookies to offer you the best possible shopping experience when you visit our website. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer hard disk, smartphone or other IT equipment. The cookie makes it possible to recognize your computer/IP-address and collect information about the pages and functions you visit.

If you do not want to accept cookies from us you need to disable cookies in your browser. If you do this, however, please be advised that certain services and functions may be unavailable to you because they rely on cookies to store the choices you make.

HAY uses cookies to improve your user experience on our website, to store the choices you make when you use our website, for example your choice of country, and to help us make ongoing improvements in the content and functions you encounter on our website. We also use cookies to target our marketing to your needs and to generate usage statistics for our website.

Some cookies are stored until you shut down your browser, while others are stored for longer.

HAY uses third-party cookies. A third-party cookie is a cookie that is placed by someone other than HAY, for example by other websites that offer content on our website, suppliers for some of the functions on our website or statistical analysis programs.

Below is a list of the third-party cookies we use:

**Name** | **Provider** | **Expiration** | **Purpose**  
---|---|---|---  
Aka_debug | Akamaized.net | Session | Used by Vimeo to track usage of their embedded video player.  
r/collect | Doubleclick.net | Session | Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behavior.  
SleekNotecookie | Sleeknote.com | 1 Year | Indicates how many times a specific Sleeknote has been shown.  
SleekNoteSessionClosed | Sleeknote.com | Session | Indicates if a specific Sleeknote has been shown this visit.  
SleeknoteReferral | Sleeknote.com | Session | Contains the referral URL that lead to the website. This is used to give the ability to show or hide a Sleeknote if they visit from a specific source, like Facebook or Google.  
SNSubscribed | Sleeknote.com | 2 years | Indicates if a visitor has subscribed to any given newsletter Sleeknote on this site. This gives the ability to hide other newsletter Sleeknotes from that user.  
SleeknoteUTM | Sleeknote.com | Session | Indicates if the user originally entered the webpage from a link containing an UTM. This gives the ability to show and hide Sleeknotes based on that UTM campaign.  
_pk_id | Sleeknote.com | 2 years | This is a cookie that tracks the visitor anonymously on the website. Can be compared to Google Analytics.  
_pk_ses | Sleeknote.com | 30 min. | This is a cookie that tracks the visitor anonymously on the website during this session. Can be compared to Google Analytics.  
_cfuid | Haystatic.com | 1 year | Used by the content network, Cloudflare, to identify trusted web traffic.  
  
If you follow a link to a third-party website, you should be aware that you may pick up additional cookies that are beyond HAY’s influence. It is up to you to check the cookie policies of any external websites.

This Privacy Policy is updated on 15.04.2019
